if the basic technical idea is behind
如果在深度学习和神经网络
【翻译/矫正/字幕：AcceptedDoge】
deep learning behind neural networks have
之前的基础技术理念
【仅供交流学习，请勿商用】
been around for decades why are they
已经存在大概几十年了 为什么
only just now taking off? in this video
它们现在才突然流行起来呢？ 在这个视频
let's go over some of the main drivers
让我们看一些使得深度学习变得如此热门
behind the rise of deep learning because
的主要驱动因素
I think this will help you that the spot
这将会帮助你
the best opportunities within your own
在你的组织机构内发现
organization to apply these to. over the
最好的时机来应用这些东西
last few years a lot of people have
在过去的几年里很多人
asked me Andrew why is deep learning
都问我 Andrew 为什么深度学习
certainly working so well and when I
能够如此有效？当我回答
answer the question this is usually the
这个问题的时候 我通常
picture I draw for them let's say we
给他们画个图
plot a figure where on the horizontal
在水平轴上画一个形状
axis we plot the amount of data we have
像这样绘制出
for a task and let's say on the vertical
我们所有任务的数据量 而在垂直轴上
axis we plot the performance on above
我们画出机器学习算法的性能
learning algorithms such as the accuracy
比如说准确率（accuracy）
of our spam classifier or our ad click
体现在垃圾邮件过滤或者广告点击预测
predictor or the accuracy of our neural
或者是我们的神经网络
net for figuring out the position of
在自动驾驶汽车时
other calls for our self-driving car. it
判断位置的准确性
turns out if you plot the performance of
根据图像可以发现 如果你
a traditional learning algorithm like
把一个传统机器学习算法的性能画出来
support vector machine or logistic
比如说支持向量机或者是逻辑回归
regression as a function of the amount
作为数据量的一个函数
of data you have you might get a curve
你可能得到一个弯曲的线
that looks like this where the
就像图中这样的
performance improves for a while as you
它的性能一开始
add more data but after a while the
在你增加更多数据时会上升 但是一段变化后
performance you know pretty much
它的性能就会像一个
plateaus right suppose your horizontal
高原一样 假设你的
lines enjoy that very well you know was
水平轴拉的很长很长
it they didn't know what to do with huge
它们不知道如何处理
amounts of data and what happened in our
规模巨大的数据 而过去十年
society over the last 10 years maybe is
在我们的这个社会
that for a lot of problems we went from
也许我们遇到的很多问题
having a relatively small amount of data
只有相对较少的数据量
to having you know often a fairly large
但是你也要知道
amount of data and all of this was
多亏了数字化社会的来临
thanks to the digitization of a society
现在的数据量都变得非常巨大
where so much human activity is now in
我们花了很多时间
the digital realm we spend so much time
活动在这些数字的领域
on the computers on websites on mobile
比如在电脑网站上 在手机软件上
apps and activities on digital devices
以及其它数字化的服务
creates data and thanks to the rise of
它们都能创建数据 同时也归功于
inexpensive cameras built into our cell
便宜的相机被配置到移动电话
phones accelerometers all sorts of
还有加速仪 各类各样的传感器
sensors in the Internet of Things we
同时在物联网领域
also just have been collecting one more
我们也收集到了越来越多的数据
and more data so over the last 20 years
仅仅在过去的20年里
for a lot of applications we just
对于很多应用 我们
accumulate a lot more data more than traditional
便收集到了大量的数据
learning algorithms were able to
远超过机器学习算法能够
effectively take advantage of and what
高效发挥它们优势的规模
neural network lead turns out that if you
神经网络展现出的是 如果你
train a small neural net then this
训练一个小型的神经网络
performance maybe looks like that
那么这个性能可能会像这样
if you train a somewhat larger neural net
如果你训练一个稍微大一点的神经网络
that's called as a medium-sized neural net
比如说一个中等规模的神经网络
to performance in something a little bit better
它在某些数据上面的性能也会更好一些
and if you train a very large neural net
如果你训练一个非常大的神经网络
then it's the form and often just keeps
它就会变成这种形式 并且保持
getting better and better. so couple of
变得越来越好 因此可以注意到两点
observations one is if you want to hit
一点是如果你想要
this very high level of performance then
获得较高的性能体现
you need two things first often you need
那么你有两个条件要完成 第一个是你需要
to be able to train a big enough neural
训练一个规模足够大的神经网络
network in order to take advantage of
以发挥数据规模量巨大
the huge amount of data and second you
的优点 另外你
need to be out here on the x axes you do
需要能画到x轴的这个位置
need a lot of data so we often say that
所以你需要很多的数据 因此我们经常说
scale has been driving deep learning
规模一直在推动深度学习的进步
progress and by scale I mean both the
这里的规模我指的也同时是
size of the neural network we need just
神经网络的规模 我们需要
a neural network with a lot of hidden units a
一个带有许多隐藏单元的神经网络
lot of parameters a lot of connections
也有许多的参数 许多的关联性
as well as scale of the data in fact
就如同需要大规模的数据一样
today one of the most reliable ways to
事实上如今最可靠的方法
get better performance in the neural
来在神经网络上获得更好的性能
network is often to either train a
往往就是要么训练一个
bigger network or throw more data at it
更大的神经网络 要么投入更多的数据
and that only works up to a point
这只能在一定程度上起作用
because eventually you run out of data
因为最终你耗尽了数据
or eventually then your network is so
或者最终你的网络是如此大规模
big that it takes too long to train but
导致将要用太久的时间去训练
just improving scale has actually taken
但是仅仅提升规模的的确确地
us a long way in the world of deep learning
让我们在深度学习的世界中摸索了很多时间
in order to make this diagram a bit more
为了使这个图更加
technically precise and just add a few
从技术上讲更精确一点
more things I wrote the amount of data
我在X轴下面已经写明的
on the x-axis technically this is amount
数据量这儿加上一个 标签（label）量
of labeled data where by label data
通过添加这个标签量
I mean training examples we have both
也就是指在训练样本时我们同时
the input X and the label Y I went to
输入X和标签Y 接下来
introduce a little bit of notation that
引入一点符号
we'll use later in this course we're
这在后面的课程中都会用到
going to use lowercase alphabet m to
我们使用小写的字母 m
denote the size of my training sets or
表示我的训练集的规模
the number of training examples
或者说训练样本的数量
this lowercase m so that's the
这个小写字母m 因此这就是
horizontal axis couple other details to
横轴 结合其他一些细节
this figure
到这个图像中
in this regime of smaller training sets
在这个小的训练集中
the relative ordering of the algorithms
各种算法的优先级
is actually not very well defined so if
事实上定义的也不是很明确
you don't have a lot of training data is
所以如果你没有大量的训练集
often up to your skill at hand
那效果会取决于你的
engineering features that determines the
特征工程能力 那将决定
performance so it's quite possible that if
最终的性能 因此很有可能
someone training an SVM is more
假设有些人训练出了一个SVM（支持向量机）
motivated to hand engineer features and
表现的更接近正确特征 然而
someone training even larger than
有些人训练的规模大一些
that may be in this small training set
可能在这个小的训练集中
regime the SVM could do better
SVM算法可以做的更好
so you know in this region to the left
因此你知道在这个图形区域的左边
of the figure the relative ordering
各种算法之间的
between the algorithms is not that well
优先级并不是定义的很明确
defined and performance depends much
最终的性能更多的是取决于
more on your skill at engine features
你在用工程选择特征方面的能力
and other normal details of the
以及算法处理方面的一些细节
algorithms and there's only in this some
只是在这某些
big data regions very large training sets
大数据规模 非常庞大的训练集
very large M regions in the right that we
也就是在右边这个m会非常的大时
more consistently see largely nerual nets
我们能更加持续地看到更大的由神经网络
dominating the other approaches and so
控制的其它方法 因此
if any of your friends ask you why are
如果你的任何某个朋友问你
neural net as you know taking off I would
为什么神经网络这么流行 我会
encourage you to draw this picture for
鼓励你也替他们画这样一个图形
them as well so I will say that in the
所以可以这么说
early days in their morning rise of deep learning
在深度学习萌芽的初期
it was scaled data and scale of
数据的规模
computation just our ability to Train
以及计算量 局限在我们
very large neural networks
对于训练一个特别大的神经网络的能力
either on a CPU or GPU that enabled us
无论是在CPU还是GPU上面 那都使得我们
to make a lot of progress but
取得了巨大的进步
increasingly especially in the last
但是渐渐地 尤其是在最近这几年
several years we've seen tremendous
我们也见证了
algorithmic innovation as well so I also
算法方面的极大创新
don't want to understate that
我可以不是那么保守地说
interestingly many of the algorithmic
有趣的是 许多算法方面的创新
innovations have been about trying to
一直是在尝试着
make neural networks run much faster so
使得神经网络运行的更快
as a concrete example one of the huge
作为一个具体的例子
breakthroughs in neural networks has been
神经网络方面的一个巨大突破是
switching from a sigmoid function which
从sigmoid函数转换
looks like this to a ReLU function
看起来像这样 到一个ReLU函数
which we talked about briefly in an
这个函数我们在之前的视频里提到过
early video that looks like this if you
它的形状就像这样
don't understand the details of one
如果你无法理解刚才我说的某个细节
about the state don't worry about it but
也不需要担心
it turns out that one of the problems of
可以知道的一个
using sigmoid functions and machine
使用sigmoid函数和
learning is that these regions
机器学习问题是 在这个区域
here where the sigmoid of the function would
也就是这个sigmoid函数的
gradient is nearly zero and so learning
梯度会接近零 所以学习的速度
becomes really slow because when you
会变得非常缓慢 因为当你
implement gradient descent and gradient
实现梯度下降以及
is zero the parameters just change very
梯度接近零的时候 参数会更新的
slowly and so learning is very slow
很慢 所以学习的速率也会变的很慢
whereas by changing the what's called
而通过改变这个被叫做
the activation function the neural
激活函数的东西 神经网络
network to use this function called the
换用这一个函数 叫做
ReLU function of the rectified linear
ReLU的函数（修正线性单元）
unit ReLU. the gradient is equal to
R e L U 它的梯度对于所有
one for all positive values of input
输入的正值都是一
right and so the gradient is much less
因此梯度不会
likely to gradually shrink to zero and
趋向逐渐减少到零
the gradient here the slope of this line
而这里的梯度 这条线的斜率
is zero on the left but it turns out
在这左边是零
that just by switching to the sigmoid
仅仅通过将Sigmod函数
function to the ReLU function has
转换成ReLU函数便能够使得
made an algorithm called gradient
一个叫做梯度下降（gradient descent）
descent work much faster and so this is
的算法运行的更快 这就是
an example of maybe relatively simple
一个或许相对比较简单
algorithm innovation but ultimately the
的算法创新的例子 但是根本上
impact of this algorithmic innovation
算法创新所带来的影响
was it really hope computation so there
实际上是对计算带来的优化 所以
remains quite a lot of examples like
有很多像这样的例子
this of where we change the algorithm
我们通过改变算法
because it allows that code to run much
使得代码运行的更快
faster and this allows us to train
这也使得我们能够训练
bigger neural networks or to do so the
规模更大的神经网络
reason of multi-client even when we have
或者是多端口的网络 即使
a large network from all the data the
我们从所有的数据中拥有了大规模的神经网络
other reason that fast computation is
快速计算显得更加重要的
important is that it turns out the
另一个原因是
process of training your network it is
训练你的神经网络的过程
very intuitive often you have an idea
很多时候是凭借直觉的
for a neural network architecture and so
往往你对神经网络架构有了一个想法
you implement your idea and code
于是你尝试实现你的想法 去写代码
implementing your idea then lets you run
实现你的想法 然后让你运行一个
an experiment which tells you how well
试验环境来告诉你
your neural network does and then by
你的神经网络效果有多好 通过
looking at it you go back to change the
参考这个结果再返回去修改
details of your neural network and then you
你的神经网络里面的一些细节
go around this circle over and over and
然后你不断的重复上面的操作
when your neural network takes a long time
当你的神经网络需要很长时间
to Train it just takes a long time to go
去训练 需要很长时间
around this cycle and there's a huge
重复这一循环 在这里就有很大的
difference in your productivity building
区别 根据你的生产效率去构建
effective neural networks when you can
更高效的神经网络 当你能够
have an idea and try it and see the work
有一个想法 试一试 看看效果如何
in ten minutes or maybe almost a day
在10分钟内 或者也许要花上一整天
worthes if you've to train your neural
如果你训练你的神经网络
network for a month which sometimes does
用了一个月的时间 有时候发生这样的事情
happened because you get a result back you know
也是值得的 因为你很快得到了一个结果
in ten minutes or maybe in a day you
在10分钟内 或者一天内
should just try a lot more ideas and be
你应该尝试更多的想法
much more likely to discover in your
那极有可能使得你的神经网络
network and it works well for your
在你的应用方面工作的更好
application and so faster computation
所以更快的计算
has really helped in terms of speeding
在提高速度方面
up the rate at which you can get an
真的有帮助 那样你就能
experimental result back and this has
更快地得到你的实验结果
really helped both practitioners of
这也同时帮助了神经网络的实验人员
neuro networks as well as researchers
和有关项目的研究人员
working at deep learning iterate much
在深度学习的工作中迭代的更快
faster and improve your ideas much
也能够更快的改进你的想法
faster and so all this has also been a
所有这些都
huge boom to the entire deep learning
使得整个深度学习的研究社群
research community which has been
变的如此繁荣
incredible with just you know inventing
包括令人难以置信地发明
new algorithms and making nonstop
新的算法和取得不间断的进步
progress on that front so these are some
这些都是开拓者在做的事情
of the forces powering the rise of deep
这些力量使得深度学习不断壮大
learning but the good news is that these
好消息是这些力量
forces are still working powerfully to
目前也正常不断的奏效
make deep learning even better. Tech Data
使得深度学习越来越好 研究表明
society is still throwing up one more
我们的社会仍然正在抛出越来越多的
digital data or take computation with
数字化数据 或者用一些特殊的
the rise of specialized hardware like
硬件来进行计算比如说
GPUs and faster networking many types of
GPU 以及更快的网络连接各种硬件
hardware I'm actually quite confident
我非常有信心
that our ability to do very large neural
我们可以做一个超级大规模的神经网络
networks or should a computation point
而计算的能力
of view will keep on getting better and
也会进一步的得到改善
take algorithms relative learning
还有算法相对的学习
research communities though continuously
研究社区连续不断的
phenomenal at innovating on the
在算法前沿 产生非凡的创新
algorithms front so because of this I
根据这些
think that we can be optimistic answer
我们可以乐观地回答
the optimistic the deep learning will
同时对深度学习保持乐观态度
keep on getting better for many years to come
在接下来的这些年它都会变的越来越好
so that let's go on to the last video of
让我们继续看最后一个视频
the section where we'll talk a little
我们会谈到的部分
bit more about what you learn from this course
更多是关于你将从这门课程中学到的知识